EMILIE D'OLNE

Room 809, Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Imperial College London, SW7 2AZ +44 7756 721158 emilie.dolne16@imperial.ac.uk www.linkedin.com/in/emiliedolne

Research interests

My current research focuses on the development of speech enhancement algorithms for hearing aids, with a specific focus on people suffering from dementia-induced hearing impairments. I am part of a clinician project in collaboration with University College London looking at hearing in dementia. My role includes the development of listening tests and assistive technologies for patients affected by dementia syndromes. I am interested in exploiting distributed microphone networks and wearable microphones for enhancement and denoising and am working with techniques such as binaural beamforming or polynomial eigenvalue decomposition (PEVD).

Education

PhD - Speech and Audio Processing

2020-PRESENT

Imperial College London, Communications and Signal Processing Research Group Interests in binaural beamforming, dereverberation, speech enhancement, wearable microphone arrays, distributed microphone networks, machine learning, deep learning.

MEng – Electrical and Electronics Engineering (First Class Honours) 2016-2020

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

Final year project: "Automatic detection of Alzheimer's Disease using speech"

Certificat d'Enseignement Secondaire Supérieur (A-levels equiv.) 2010-2016

Athénée Royal Charles Rogier Liège 1, Liège, Belgium

Projects

Synergising Markers, Tests and Technologies to Enable Real-world Hearing in Alzheimer's and Related dementias (SMarTTER HeAR) 2022-PRESENT

Discovery Research Grant (RNID and Alzheimer's research UK), University College London

Responsible for the "technology" side and participating in the design of listening tests.

Experience

Vice-Chair, Treasurer

2021-PRESENT

Imperial College IEEE Student branch

Organisation of technical seminars and workshops, monitoring of the branch's finances.

Postgraduate Student Representative

2021-PRESENT

Imperial College London, Communications and Signal Processing Research Group

Representing students' interests within the department and at the university.

Teaching Assistant

2019-PRESENT

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

Teaching, development of materials, assessment, and support.

Research Intern SUMMER 2019

Imperial College London, Speech and Audio Processing Laboratory

Gaze-directed beamforming for hearing aids in collaboration with Cardiff University.

Publications

- [1] **E. d'Olne**, V. W. Neo, and P. A. Naylor, "Speech Enhancement in Distributed Microphone Arrays Using Polynomial Eigenvalue Decomposition", 2022 [Submitted to *Proc. Eur. Signal Process. Conf. (EUSIPCO)*]
- [2] **E. d'Olne**, A. H. Moore, and P. A. Naylor, "Model-based beamforming for wearable microphone arrays", in *Proc. Eur. Signal Process. Conf. (EUSIPCO)*, Dublin, Ireland, 2021.

Awards

Institute of Engineering and Technology (IET) Prize

2020

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

Dean's List for Academic Excellence

2018,2019,2020

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

Skills and Languages

Technical skills

MATLAB (advanced), Python (intermediate), TensorFlow (intermediate), C++ (intermediate), GitHub (intermediate), Linux (intermediate), HTML (intermediate)

Languages

French (bilingual), Spanish (intermediate), German (intermediate)